

ALPER AKTAŞ
FRONT-END DEVELOPER

CONTACT INFO

\ +90 534 621 81 05

contact@aktasalper.com

in /aktasalper/

🔇 aktasalper.com

• Avcılar, İstanbul

EDUCATION

Ege University

English Language and Literature **2017 - 2022**

Küçükçekmece High School

Foreign Language Class **2015** - **2017**

Çakmaklı Cumhuriyet High School

2013 - 2015

LANGUAGES

Turkish - Native

English - Aptis C1

REFERENCES

Gökhan Kurt

Software Development Manager

\ +90 536 393 59 45

Uğur Yılmaz

Front-end Team Lead

Etstur

**** +90 545 551 19 93

ABOUT ME

I am a 24 year old English Language and Literature graduate interested in software development. My entry to software development began with taking online courses on Python and building small projects with it. After I worked as a front-end developer intern, I have been primarily focusing on web development. I am currently working at Etstur as a software development assistant.

EXPERIENCES

JUL 25, 2022 - PRESENT

SOFTWARE DEVELOPMENT ASSISTANT

Etstur

Partaking in the Front-end transitional rewrite of Etstur's B2B hotel management application which was written on Java and FTL, and will transition into a React / Java Spring Boot stack.

Taking the lead Front-end developer role for Etstur's new contract management application from its inception to its production stages, making it the first ever project to be fully written in React to reach production stage at Etstur. Then, assisting the new team assigned to the project after the production stage with hand-over and maintenance.

OCT 2021 - NOV 2021

FRONT-END DEVELOPER INTERN

1Pixel Digital Agency

Coding functional and responsive sections of pages in HTML based on provided page designs, integrating these sections into Shopify themes to provide customizable components to merchants, and integrating dynamic store data into page elements using Shopify Liquid templating language.

MAY 2020 - AUG 2021

FREELANCE VIDEO EDITOR

Freelancer.com

Editing & creating advertisement, music and presentation videos for clients.

SKILLS & FAMILIARITY

FRONT-END

- > React
- > TypeScript
- > Vite / webpack
- > Vitest / lest
- > react-testing-library / Playwright

FAMILIAR WITH

- > Next.js
- > Node.js

CERTIFICATES

React (Basic)

HackerRank
10 Apr, 2022

Rest API (Intermediate)

HackerRank 11 Apr, 2022

Python Programming: From Beginner to

Advanced

Bilgi Teknolojileri ve İletişim Kurumu

19 Aug, 2021

SQL (Basic) HackerRank 12 Aug, 2021